National Service Secretariat Records
National Service Secretariat (US) Records
1959-1991
National Service Secretariat (U.S.)
49 linear ft.
Papers of the private non-profit organization founded in 1966 which promotes national service and acts as a clearinghouse for information about it. Director: Donald J. Eberly. Collection includes organization records, including correspondence, legislative files, conference and project proposals; and printed material, including books, clippings, newsletters, pamphlets, proceedings, reports, and videocassettes pertaining to community service, military draft, the Peace Corps, service learning, youth employment, and voluntarism.
149732
Biographical History
The National Service Secretariat is a private non-profit organization whose purpose is to act as a clearinghouse for information regarding national service and to promote the idea that young Americans can serve their country and humankind as effectively in civilian service as in military service. The organization was founded in 1966 by Donald J. Eberly, who served as its Executive Director from 1966-1994. His National Service for Peace proposal of 1958 was one of the sources of Senator Hubert Humphrey's Peace Corps legislation, and his convening of the first National Service Conference in 1966 launched a nationwide debate on the issue.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The National Service Secretariat Records span nearly forty years of the American non-profit organization and provide a comprehensive picture of its activities. The collection includes office files, material relating to national service conferences and legislation, files on various projects, and a considerable amount of resource material, some audiovisual but the majority printed.
Office files include individuals (Bill Clinton, Eli Ginzberg, Gary Hart, Hubert Humphrey, Richard Nixon, John D. Rockefeller), organizations (Atlanta Urban Corps, California Conservation Corps, Ford Foundation, Junior League, Kellogg Foundation, National Council of Churches), publishers (Pergamon Press, Penguin), and general topics (conscientious objectors, draft options, minorities, surveys).
Conferences includes material from National Service Conferences from 1966-1993 (not all years are represented). National service legislation contains material related to proposed laws and legislative bodies. Projects comprises material relating to specific projects undertaken by the National Service Secretariat.
Resource material (by subject) consists of nearly thirty boxes of material on ACTION, education, community service, conscientious objectors, international service, military, Peace Corps, poverty, tutoring, voluntarism, and other topics. Resource material (by format) includes books, newsletters, and audio- and videotapes.
Arrangement of the Collection
All series are arranged alphabetically.
Related Material
See also the
Donald Eberly Papers
.
Subject and Genre Headings
Politics, government and public administration; Activism and social reform; Eberly, Donald J.; Coalition for National Service.; National Service Secretariat (U.S.), Archives.; Peace Corps (U.S.); Military service, Voluntary.; National service.; National service -- Law and legislation.; National service -- United States.; Service -- Compulsory non-military -- United States.; Voluntarism.; Volunteer workers in social service -- Training of.; Volunteers.; Youth -- Employment -- United States.; Youth -- Government policy -- United States.; Youth -- Services for -- United States.; Young volunteers in community development -- United States.; Audiocassettes.; Books.; Correspondence.; Newsletters.; Pamphlets.; Reports.; Videocassettes.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the National Service Secretariat and Donald J. Eberly, 1993.
Inventory
- Office files (general correspondence)
  - Alphabetical
    - A (Box 1)
    - ACTION, 1970; 1983,; undated; 21 folders (Box 8)
      See also Resource material (by subject): ACTION (Boxes 15, 16)
    - American Veterans Committee (Box 1)
    - Amnesty, 1973 (Box 1)
    - Assumptions for National Service (Box 1)
    - Atlanta Urban Corps (Box 1)
    - Atlantic Council (Box 1)
    - Azaro, Stanley R. (Box 1)
    - B, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Barbados (Box 1)
    - Boston - City Year (Box 1)
    - Bramson, Leo (Box 1)
    - Bureau of the Budget (Box 1)
    - C, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - California Conservation Corps (Box 1)
    - California Group NSF, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Cambodia (Box 1)
    - Canada (Box 1)
    - Campus Compact, See Projects (Miscellaneous): Campus Compact (Box 13)
    - Carnegie Corporation of New York (Box 1)
    - Carnegie Council Kerr (Box 1)
    - Center for Strategic and International Studies (Box 1)
    - Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions (Box 1)
    - Chickering, Sherman (Box 1)
    - China (Box 1)
    - Civilian Conservation Corps, See Projects (Miscellaneous): Civilian Conservation Corps (Box 13)
    - Clinton, William, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Coalition for National Service, See Projects (Miscellaneous): Coalition for National Service (Box 13)
    - Committee for the Study of National Service (Box 1)
    - Conscientious Objectors, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - COOL, See Projects (Miscellaneous): COOL (Box 13)
    - Coordinating Committee for International Voluntary Service (Box 2)
    - Costa Rica (Box 2)
    - Council on Youth Opportunity (Box 2)
    - Cuba, Dec. 1977 (Box 2)
    - Cullinan, Terrence (Box 2)
    - Current History (Box 2)
    - D (Box 2)
    - [Arthur Vining] Davis Foundations (Box 2)
    - Debate Survey, Jan. 1969 (Box 2)
    - Debates (miscellaneous) (Box 2)
    - Dickson, Alec (Box 2)
    - D.C. Service Corps (Box 2)
    - Draft Options, 1966 (Box 2)
    - E, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Eames, Earl W. (Box 2)
    - Eberly, Donald J., 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Education for Action (Box 2)
    - Ellingson, M., 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Encampment for Citizenship (Box 2)
    - EPIC Los Angeles (Box 2)
    - Everett Foundation (Box 2)
    - Education and World Affairs/Overseas Educational Service (Box 2)
    - F (Box 2)
    - Fetzer Foundation (Box 2)
    - Ford Foundation (Box 2)
    - Ford Group (Box 2)
    - Forensic Quarterly (Box 2)
    - Foundations, 1984 (Box 2)
    - Foundations, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Foundations: No Formal Grant Submission (Box 3)
    - Foxfire, 1969 (Box 3)
    - France (Box 3)
    - G, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - General (Box 3)
    - Ginzberg, Eli (Box 3)
    - Global, mixed (Box 3)
    - Great Britain (Box 3)
    - H, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Hall, Edward (Box 3)
    - Hart, Gary (Box 3)
    - Hatfield, Bill (Box 3)
    - Hatfield, Mark (Box 3)
    - Hazen Foundation (Box 3)
    - Hoover Institute (Box 3)
    - Human Environment Center, See Projects (Miscellaneous): Human Environment Center (Box 13)
    - Humphrey, Hubert (Box 3)
    - I/J (Box 3)
    - India (Box 3)
    - Institute for Local Self Reliance (Box 3)
    - Interface (Box 3)
    - International, 1965 1966 (Box 3)
    - International Youth Foundation (Box 3)
    - International Youth Year (Box 3)
    - Jackson Foundation (Box 3)
    - Johnson Foundation (Box 3)
    - Joint Committee on Mental Health of Children (Box 3)
    - Jossey Bass Inc., Publishers (Box 3)
    - Junior League (Box 3)
    - K (Box 3)
    - Katz, Michael B. (Box 3)
    - [W. K.] Kellogg Foundation, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Knoell, Dorothy (Box 3)
    - L (Box 3)
    - Lessinger, Leon (Box 3A)
    - Little, Roger (Box 3A)
    - M, 3 folders (Box 3A)
    - [John D. and Catherine T.] MacArthur Foundation (Box 3A)
    - McCloskey, Paul W., 2 folders (Box 3A)
    - Manitou Foundation (Box 3A)
    - Marmion, Harry (Box 3A)
    - Martin, Reed (Box 3A)
    - Mead, Margaret (Box 3A)
    - Michigan (Box 3A)
    - Minnesota (Box 3A)
    - Minorities (Box 3A)
    - Moskos, Charles C. (Box 3A)
    - Multnomah County (Box 3A)
    - N, 2 folders (Box 3A)
    - National Advisory Commission on Civil Disorders (Box 3A)
    - National Advisory Commission on Selective Service, See Projects (Miscellaneous): National Advisory Commission on Selective Service (Box 13)
    - National Commission on Resources for Youth, Inc (NCRY), 3 folders (Box 3A)
    - National Commission on Youth (Box 3A)
    - National Council for the Social Studies (Box 3A)
    - National Council of Churches (Box 3A)
    - National Council of Women (Box 3A)
    - National Service Clippings, 1979 (Box 3A)
    - National Service Organization, See Projects (Miscellaneous): National Service Organization (Box 14)
    - National Service Secretariat
      - Advisory Board, 4 folders (Box 3A)
      - Board of Trustees, 5 folders (Box 4)
      - By-laws, See Incorporation
      - Evaluation matrix, 1984 (Box 4)
      - Finances
        - Federal (Box 4)
        - Fundraising, 2 folders (Box 4)
        - Incoming (Box 4)
        - Tax exemption (Box 4)
      - Incorporation (Box 4)
      - Milestones (Box 4)
      - Prospectus, 1969 (Box 4)
      - Publicity
        - Flyer (Box 4)
        - Press releases (Box 4)
      - Miscellaneous, 1950s (Box 4)
    - National Service Survey, 1966; 1967 (Box 4)
    - New Orleans Service Learning Program, Inc. (Box 4)
    - New World (Box 4)
    - New York Affairs (NYA) (Box 4)
    - New York City Talk, 23 Feb. 1989 (Box 4)
    - Newsletter Items, 1968; 1969; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Nigeria/American Friends Service Committee Inc. (Box 4)
    - Nigeria National Youth Service Corps (Box 4)
    - Nixon, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - North Carolina Internship Office (Box 4)
    - O (Box 4)
    - Office of Economic Opportunity (Box 4)
    - Ogilvy Group (Box 4)
    - Ohio (Box 4)
    - Organization :: Response (Box 4)
    - Organizations (miscellaneous), 1968; 1969 (Box 4)
    - P/Q (Box 5)
    - Papers, 1966 (Box 5)
    - Papers, Speeches, etc. on National Service, 1966 (Box 5)
    - Pergamon Press, Inc. Book Contributors (Box 5)
    - Pergamon Press, Inc. Book Promotion (Box 5)
    - Pergamon Press, Inc. Endorsements and Reviews (Box 5)
    - Pergamon Press, Inc. Sherraden, Michael (Box 5)
    - Personnel (Box 5)
    - Point Four Youth Corps (Box 5)
    - Pre Publication Correspondence (Box 5)
    - Presidential Committee on Manpower (Box 5)
    - Press (miscellaneous) (Box 5)
    - Public Relations: News Releases, Speeches & DJE Letters to Editors, 1966; 1967 (Box 5)
    - Public Relations: Replies to News & Magazine Articles, 1966; 1967 (Box 5)
    - R (Box 5)
    - Requests Persons Wishing to Serve, 1968 (Box 5)
    - Research bibliography general (Box 5)
    - Research: Education, 1966; 1967 (Box 5)
    - Research: International (Box 5)
    - Research: National Service Pilot Programs (Box 5)
    - Riesman, David (Box 5)
    - Rimberg, Felix (Box 5)
    - Rockefeller, John D. III (Box 5)
    - Roosevelt Centennial Youth Project (Box 5)
    - Rotary International (Box 5)
    - Russell Sage Foundation, 3 folders (Box 5)
    - S, 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Saltonstall, William (Box 5)
    - Service curriculum (Box 5)
    - Service Opportunities System (Box 5)
    - Seventeen Survey (Box 5)
    - [Alfred P.] Sloan Foundation (Box 5)
    - Southern Regional Education Board (SREB), See Projects (Miscellaneous): Southern Regional Education Board (SREB) (Box 14)
    - Southwestern Bell (Box 5)
    - SRI International (Box 5)
    - Stanford Research Institute (SRI, See Projects (Miscellaneous): Stanford Research Institute (SRI) (Box 14)
    - Statement (Box 5)
    - [W. Clement & Jessie V.] Stone Foundation (Box 5)
    - Survey of Corporations' Employment Policies, 1966 (Box 5)
    - Syracuse University (Box 6)
    - T (Box 6)
    - Teacher Corps (Box 6)
    - U/V (Box 6)
    - University of Minnesota Living Learning Center (Box 6)
    - Urban Corps, 5 folders (Box 6)
    - Volt Technical Corporation (Box 6)
    - Volunteer Community Activities Clearing House (Box 6)
    - Volunteers for International Technical Assistance (Box 6)
    - W, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - World Future Society (Box 6)
    - Youth Engaged in Service to America (YES to America) (Box 6)
  - Chronological
    - "Early correspondence", 1959; 1960 (Box 6)
    - 1965, 1967, 7 folders (Box 6)
    - 1967, 1985, 33 folders (Box 7)
    - 1986, 1994, 9 folders (Box 8)
- Conferences
  - 1966
    - May 7 National Service Conference, 4 folders (Box 9)
    - Sept. 23-25 National Service Workshop (Box 9)
    - Nov. 11-12 National Conference on the Draft (Box 9)
    - Nov. 17-20 National Collegiate Conference on Selective Service Reform (Box 9)
    - Nov. 28 Dec. 2 Draft Week Conference (Box 9)
    - Dec. 4-7 Conference on the Draft, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Dec. 10 United World Federalists (Box 9)
  - 1967
    - Mar. 14-16 National Council of Women (Box 9)
    - Apr. 2-4 National Service Conference, 11 folders (Box 9)
    - May 17-19 - Conference on the training of Young People for Rescue, Relief and Service (Box 9)
    - Oct. 22-24 - Youth's Better Way: Youth, UNESCO, and Fresh Approaches to World Problems (Box 9)
  - 1971
    - Mar. 14-17 26th National Conference of Higher Education (Box 10)
    - Sept. 7-11 Annual Meeting of the American Political Science Association (Box 10)
  - 1976
    - Apr. 9-10 In the Matter of the Universal Youth Service Conference, 7 folders (Box 10)
  - 1977
    - June 16-18 Senior Conference on National Compulsory Service (Box 10)
  - 1980
    - June 19-21 Symposium on Military Manpower and National Public Service, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - 1988
    - July 7-9 National Service: An Action Agenda for the 1990s, 5 folders (Box 10)
      See also Resource material (by format): Miscellaneous audiocassettes: An Action Agenda for the 1990's (Box 50)
  - 1990
    - June 14-16 National Service Conference (Box 11)
  - 1991
    - July 19-21 Youth Service and Democracy in the 21st Century: Creating a New Institution, 5 folders (Box 11)
      See also Resource material (by format): Miscellaneous audiocassettes: Youth Service and Democracy in the 21st Century: Creating a New Institution (Box 50)
  - 1993
    - April 21-23 - Building a Consensus on National Service (Box 11)
- National Service legislation
  - Armed Services Committees (Box 11)
  - Bayh Bingham (Box 11)
  - Congress, 6 folders (Box 11)
  - Education and Labor, 1979 (Box 12)
  - Legislation, 1979; 1980; 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous, 13 folders (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous (3 folders of 16), 3 folders (Box 13)
- Projects (Miscellaneous)
  - ACTION, See: Office files (general correspondence): Alphabetical: ACTION (Box 8) Resource material (by subject): ACTION (Boxes 15, 16)
  - Campus Compact, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Civilian Conservation Corps (Box 13)
  - Coalition for National Service, 3 folders (Box 13)
  - COOL (Box 13)
  - Human Environment Center, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - National Advisory Commission on Selective Service (NACSS), 1966; 1967; 5 folders (Box 13)
  - National Service Organization, 4 folders (Box 14)
  - Southern Regional Education Board (SREB)
    - General, 5 folders (Box 14)
    - Atlanta Service Learning Conference (Box 14)
    - Labor Department Report (Box 14)
    - Manpower Survey (Box 14)
    - March 6 meeting (Box 14)
  - Stanford Research Institute (SRI)
    - Alderson Broaddus (Box 14)
    - Bridgeport (Box 14)
    - Idaho State (Box 14)
    - Introduction (Box 14)
    - Iowa Wesleyan (Box 14)
    - Keuka (Box 14)
    - Oregon (Box 14)
    - Pikeville (Box 14)
    - South Colorado State (Box 14)
    - Stanford Research Institute (Box 14)
    - Vista Survey (Box 14)
    - Wilmington (Box 14)
    - Yale & Bridgeport (Box 14)
- Resource material, by subject
  - ACTION (Box 15, 16)
    See also Office files (general correspondence): Alphabetical: ACTION (Box 8)
  - Community Service (Box 17)
  - Conscientious Objectors & Alternative Service (Box 18)
  - Conservation (Box 19)
  - Eberly, Donald J./NSS Papers and Publicity (Box 20)
  - Education (Box 21, 22)
  - Employment (Box 23)
  - Health/Arts/Energy (Box 24)
  - International Secretariat for Volunteer Service/Coordinating Committee for International Voluntary Service (ISVC/CCIVS) (Box 25)
  - International Service (Box 26)
  - International Service Programs (miscellaneous) (Box 27)
  - Legislation (Box 28)
  - Military (Box 29, 30)
  - National Service in Canada (Box 31)
  - National Service in the United Kingdom, See International Service Programs (miscellaneous) (Box 27)
  - National Service Proposals (Box 32, 33)
  - Peace Corps (Box 34, 35)
  - Poverty (Box 36)
  - Service Learning (Box 37)
  - Soviet American Youth Service (SAYS) (Box 38)
  - Tutoring (Box 39)
  - United Nations (Box 40)
  - Voluntarism (Box 41)
  - Women (Box 42)
  - Youth (Box 43, 44)
- Resource material, miscellaneous (arranged by format)
  - Miscellaneous books (Box 45-47)
  - Miscellaneous newsletters (Box 48)
  - Miscellaneous audio recordings
    Tapes are stored in order by tape number. All are standard audiocassettes. Titles are given as written on the tape. All titles consist of a single cassette unless otherwise noted. "DJE" throughout refers to Donald James Eberly, director of the NSS.
    - An Action Agenda for the 1990's (1), 07/07/1988; nat_serv_sec_041; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 50)
    - An Action Agenda for the 1990's (2), 07/08/1988; nat_serv_sec_042; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 50)
    - An Action Agenda for the 1990's (3), 07/08/1988; nat_serv_sec_043; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 50)
    - An Action Agenda for the 1990's (4), 07/09/1988; nat_serv_sec_044; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 50)
    - Colonial Service Organization of National Service Secretariat, 04/04/1967; nat_serv_sec_005; 1/4 inch audio tape; running time 180:00 (Box 51)
    - D. J. E. [Donald James Eberly] on Karen Grace/Brian Simek Program: WHAM Radio - Rochester, NY, 04/11/1989; nat_serv_sec_032; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 50)
    - DJE [Donald James Eberly] radio talk show, Aug 1983; nat_serv_sec_034; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 50)
    - Don Eberly, Paul Benzaguin and Howard Nelson, 03/07/1961; nat_serv_sec_013; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 51)
    - [Donald James] Eberly and Moskos (1 and 2), 10/18/1983; nat_serv_sec_037; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 50)
    - [Donald James] Eberly - Moskos (3), 10/18/1983; nat_serv_sec_036; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 50)
    - [Donald James] Eberly - Moskos (Last one), 10/18/1983; nat_serv_sec_038; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 50)
    - [Donald James] Eberly on Fred Fiske Show, WAMU-FM (both sides), 08/19/1983; nat_serv_sec_033; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 50)
    - Education and World Affairs, 05/07/1966; nat_serv_sec_015; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 50)
    - Jim Bohannon SHow (11-12): McCurdy and [Donald James] Eberly, 03/04/1989; nat_serv_sec_039; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 50)
    - Jim Bohannon Show (12-1): McCurdy and [Donald James] Eberly, 03/04/1989; nat_serv_sec_040; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 50)
    - [National Service and Education Conference] Beginning of Conference, 04/01/1967; nat_serv_sec_014; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 51)
    - National Service and Education Conference, 04/03/1967; nat_serv_sec_002; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 51)
    - National Service Secretariat [Conference] Luncheon in Colonial Room [and East Room between 3:00 and 5:25 p.m.], 04/04/1967; nat_serv_sec_007; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 51)
    - National Service Secretariat [Conference]: Continuation of Discussion into Senator Javits, 04/04/1967; nat_serv_sec_008; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 51)
    - National Service Secretariat Selection and Training, Positions and Discussion, Continuation of Discussion, 04/04/1967; nat_serv_sec_010; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 51)
    - National Service: Centralized or Decentralized, 04/04/1967; nat_serv_sec_017; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 50)
    - [National Service and Education Conference] National Service and the Military [Part I], 04/03/1967; nat_serv_sec_016; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 50)
    - [National Service and Education Conference] National Service and the Military [Part II], 04/03/1967; nat_serv_sec_012; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 51)
    - [National Service and Education Conference] National Service Secretariat Luncheon, 04/03/1967; nat_serv_sec_011; Dr. Gene Lyons; Peace Corps, Carp; Richard Grahm, Teacher Corps; Jack Howard, Department of Labor; Brown, Vista; David Quire, Job Corps; Discussion; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 51)
    - [National Service and Education Conference] National Service Secretariat Mayflower Hotel, Washington D.C., 04/03/1967; nat_serv_sec_004; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 51)
    - National Service and Society, New York Suite, Apr 2 [no year]; featuring Mrs. Louis J. Robbins, Leon Bramson, Reed Martin, and Chairman Samuel D. Proctor; possibly part of 1966 or 1967 conference; nat_serv_sec_009; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 51)
    - National Services Secretariat Activities and Criteria, 04/04/1967; nat_serv_sec_006; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 51)
    - National Service Conference, 05/07/1966; nat_serv_sec_003; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 51)
    - National Youth Service: A Global Perspective (1), 06/18/1992; nat_serv_sec_045; notes in red marker: "Side 1 - Thursday; Side 2 - Thurs late, Momoh Fri".; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Box 50)
    - [National Youth Service: A Global Perspective (2)], No tape 2 was in the collection when donated.
    - National Youth Service: A Global Perspective (3), 06/20/1992; nat_serv_sec_046; notes in red marker: "Side 2 - Mutambara Hebart"; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Box 50)
    - National Youth Service: A Global Perspective (4), 06/1992; nat_serv_sec_047; note on side 2 reads: "Sunam - Shervadu, chibbevs"; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Box 50)
    - National Youth Service: A Global Perspective (5), 06/1992; nat_serv_sec_048; note in red marker reads: "Side 1 - weekend; side 2 - weak. Nation Followers #5"; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Box 50)
    - National Youth Service: A Global Perspective (6), 06/21/1992; nat_serv_sec_049; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Box 50)
    - Phillips Academy Program for WRUL, 06/29/1954; nat_serv_sec_001; 1/4 inch audio tape; running time 27:30 (Box 51)
    - Side B: Dan Evans Interview; Side A: Last 10 min of Prokofiev Piano Conc., Nov 1983; nat_serv_sec_035; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 50)
    - Sunday early; Sunday mid-late, 06/21/1992; nat_serv_sec_055; note reads: "Side 1 - 6-20-92 #5"; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Box 50)
    - Youth Service and Democracy in the 21st Century: Creating a New Institution (1), 07/19/1991; nat_serv_sec_050; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 50)
    - [Youth Service and Democracy in the 21st Century: Creating a New Institution (2)], No tape 2 was in the collection when donated.
    - Youth Service and Democracy in the 21st Century: Creating a New Institution (3), Jul 1991; nat_serv_sec_051; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 50)
    - Youth Service and Democracy in the 21st Century: Creating a New Institution (4), 07/21/1991; nat_serv_sec_052; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 50)
    - Youth Service and Democracy in the 21st Century: Creating a New Institution (5), 07/21/1991; nat_serv_sec_053; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 50)
    - [Blank ?], 06/20/1992; nat_serv_sec_054; Note reads: "Side 1 - Actually 6/9; 6-20-92 #3".; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Box 50)
  - Miscellaneous video recordings, Titles are given as written on the tape.
    - CCC/Soviet Work exchange, Sacramento work, Feb 1991; nat_serv_sec_030; Soviet youth at work in Sacramento.; VHS (Box 49)